hi everyone my name is Delan Grant and
uh welcome welcome to my
presentation on manual life insurance
okay
um name of insurance company for B
Mobility that represents the employees
for shortterm disability right it's man
life insurance company okay the location
is in Montreal Quebec please feel free
to review here Montreal Quebec Canada
okay and
um manone life I had a previous
encounter with man life in
2002 and it was not a pleasant
experience I think I have made mention
in my previous presentation right on
this insurance company this insurance
company is bias is there for the company
and not for the employees okay please
feel free to pause and read as I go
along I'm going to try to go fast okay
thank you
damages criminal acts man life insurance
company right they're also responsible
for everything that happened in my life
thereafter to cover up their deception
including murder attempts okay I'm going
to um my injury was injury was in 2016
so I will begin 2016 what led up to my
um termination from my job of 20 years
okay please feel free to pause and read
it as I go along
thanks workplace safety breach injured
on the job May 2016 to December
2016 June 2016 you are already aware
that my hand was in pain in June 2016
and and I told my supervisor in July
2016 it became stolen I told my
supervisor and I was still working I was
ignored right and I I had to work in my
condition okay it was a fastpaced
environment I can imagine what I was
going through
okay and here I did a point out um with
Belle okay this is what happened I
provided thank God I I was putting
things in writing so everything is there
showing that I was um asking for
assistance you know so there was a
safety breach okay so please feel free
to pause and read okay but remember I've
already went through on um the
presentation um with B Mobility okay
thanks please feel free to read okay and
as I said I'll be going through quickly
okay however with the I was working with
broken tools and all that I was in an
awkward position at work the information
here I extracted it okay just for you to
read it says here people of all ages can
develop this condition which usually
happens when the tendons are strained by
prolonged or repetitive use of the hand
Rapid or forceful hand use okay and yes
it was okay and it also said or use of
the hand or arm in an awkward position
so my keyboard was too flat when I was
set up ergonomic before the the
ergonomist uh she placed the keyboard on
the the Little Foot there and she set me
up and with the lighting and whatever I
was not set up at all so um remember I
was too good at my job so right this
time they need to get rid of me so what
they did they demoted me put me in a
position that I did not know about and
the it was a fastpac environment that's
why I hurt my hand so quickly my poor
little hand all these years working
never experienced such um a rapid
forceful use of hand and in the awkward
positioning and you know yeah so please
feel free to pause and read if you like
okay okay this information I've also
extracted for you to read okay and it
says here however repe repetitive strain
this is 10 and9 this injury right
however repetitive strain um such as
long hours of typing yes we were typing
for 7 hours you can hardly get a
bathroom break actually yeah 7 hours
okay symptoms is typically mild case in
typically mild cases when treated
quickly mine wasn't treated quickly I
was working 12 weeks okay treated
quickly and with no other complicating
factors and I did point out in my
medical records the distort the
Distortion of my medical records that
the complicating factors they use this
by distorting my my my medical records
to make it seem as if I had other
medical issue that's why I had the
injury and the injury is not for Bell
can you imagine what what they did just
to cover up for this company B Mobility
right a man in life is the same and life
is just as guilty okay be free to pause
and read if you wish thanks
no accommodation June 15 2016 okay I
already went through that there was no
accommodation and I went to the walk-in
clinic and that's when the doctor um
told me I Deco citis so I should cease
typing be free to pause and read thank
you here confirmed deck of intendance in
on September 3rd okay 2016 Great Lakes
Medical thank you this Medical Center
honestly if it was for this Medical
Center I would not have proof but there
are walking Clinic there was there are
walking clinic so understand here that
the that the ministry doesn't really
recognize a walking CL that's what I'm
told they were more recognized your
family doctor my family doctor wasn't
doing it for me but Great Lakes was
doing it thank you Great
Lakes here I was sent by um the doctor
from Great Lakes told me to go to my
family doctor and um as I did May
mention I saw my family doctor on
September 6 2016 at the Humber Regional
Hospital Church site and that's when he
gave me right um this note please refuse
to pause and read thank
you and again my doctor provided this to
man life this is a report the form that
has to be filled out for all employees
right and it says here
tenidis right wrist that's what it says
and it it says my time to return to work
was unknown and he also said I have it
here enlarged that um ten it takes a
long time to improve and I had to wait I
had to wait to see a specialist okay and
I did make mention before and I did not
um I Dr James Chang he said he was
unsuccessful in providing a specialist
because um um yeah it was unsuccessful
so I didn't get a specialist I didn't
see the specialist until the following
year January 26 2017 I had to wait 4
months extra so from September you know
um to January I had to wait four months
for a
specialist however my injury was from
June bear that in mind okay here's a
better view of the information here okay
thanks it wasn't for Great Lakes okay I
was sent for pH therapy immediately or
was provided any examination by Dr James
Chang I asked Dr James Chang about
physiotherapy this was informed by you
know family friend because um um I was
out there at home waiting and I know
that my company wouldn't have it okay so
I went Dr James Chang and I got a
requisition okay for physio okay it was
a walk in clinic Great Lakes Medical
that took the initiative to request an
examination for my painful swollen right
hand visited Dr James Chang in October
but still was unsuccessful in private
providing a specialist so here it was
Great Lakes Medical Doctor um FAL I
think yes sent me for yeah an ultrasound
and it confirmed tentis and this was the
11th of October 2016
okay I saw Dr James Chang in October and
I he complet a physical fitness
report okay please feel free to pause
and
read here it says it it was giv
information on my hand tenis a forarm
forearm and thumb it was that's not my
it wasn't just my wrist area it's my
entire uh arm you know so um
here he said able to do work that does
not involve typ pain I do not know what
my why my doctor wrote that because no I
was in terrible pain I had sleepless
night so I could not go to work I was in
terrible shape hey
okay here he
indicated um unknown they're asking when
I can return it says
unknown um yet unknown um and it says
will refer to plastic so you notice in
October not lying on my doctor I still
did not see a specialist be feel free to
pause and
read there it is
okay and I got um this information yeah
uh yes as the day when I saw Dr James CH
I guess he did this diagram this is his
notes say Dr James Chang okay so on
October 13 2016 I need drew that of the
hand they were the swelling okay and
swelling on the thumb and swelling in my
risk okay I would tell you my hand my
risk area was black and blue that's what
it was
okay this is the um note on October 13th
see from September 15 that when I saw
him if I didn't go to him on October 13
I would not have been sent to Physio so
I got this for phys therapy okay
okay
physiotherapy so I I went on October
25th some someone recommended me to this
place okay um I saw snea Simon she
recorded only got injured at work okay I
can see that okay and uh and uh My Pain
Scale was 9 out of 10 okay so um my
thing is
um that I
told Simon recorded only got injured on
on at job at work she said that it was
too late to claim the bless IB that's
what she told me and this was word of
mouth okay she was just telling me I
told her um you know I heard of WSB and
all that and she said it was too late to
claim um because IND indur happened from
June and this is now October okay um she
on only six session with her because she
had emergency maternity leave um there
was 2 week a 2 we Gap after a 2 we Gap
right that further delayed my recovery
since the clinic had to find a
replacement in the fourth sessions near
asimon realized that the pain was also
up to my elbow that's when she's
realizing I thought she knew what she
was doing that the pain was up to my
elbow and not just my risk era right
that she had concentrated on during the
previous sessions right there was not
much done in 3 weeks twice per week for
20 minutes or less only six sessions so
I had to wait which made the previous
sessions of nonone effect okay I lost
two weeks of physio the replacement
brick Ram Jani took over the week of
November 27 2016 there were no exercises
for my hand given by this Clinic none
whatsoever okay all just 20 minutes or
less they said 20 minutes but I did not
get 20 minutes I timed it okay please
feel free to pause and read thank
you
here as she made mention in her notes
deavan tentis okay and she is telling
the procedure she said treatment she
indicated ice 10 minutes brace and rest
okay all right and I started treatment
on the 27th of October and I didn't real
I didn't not get this report until
something happened in December and I
asked for a copy and that's when I
recognized that this the SN assignment
SN assignment was actually doing me
wrong she wasn't really recording my
treatment and what she was doing she was
actually making small conversations and
misconstruing my my conversations I do
not know if was a language barrier but I
just just I felt it was an intent to
deceive because again again on November
1st after my first visit on the second
visit her report says reports feels
better and I would tell you that wsib
took that note took it that I was
feeling better my injury was 4 months
and 11 days physiotherapist wrote that I
was feeling better on my second visit
and then other little things would
indicate it would suggest that I was
using my hand and causing further damage
and and and it's like I told this
physiotherapist SN s that I I am unable
to use my hand and she has been
suggestive in her notes okay please feel
free to pause and read thank you if you
can and uh here big Ram at the time he
was my new um physiotherapist I guess
Manny life wasn't aware that there was a
change in of the Guard so here bck ramit
right on December 12 2016 wrote um it
did say dec of anusitis that is it I
brought this um and I enlarged it okay
it says here um they wanted to know if
um if is the employee able to work while
receiving treatment and he said no I
will not support this decision as the
Pain Scale is 9 out of 10 you can see
that swelling is present there even
while um working even while moving right
the risk and thumb slightly
um it uh whatever this word is I guess
it it irritates the pain it I it's
painful for me then that's what it
actually exactly saying please be free
to pause and read
okay and here please for you to pause
and read she's unable to do any
endurance task as continued movement
leads to pain right please you know and
and he mentioned about the swelling okay
all right so the information here you
can see it here this is the date bigam
Jani right is the same information that
I enlarged again they're asking me if I
can return to work and he said no she's
not she is not as she has a lot of
swelling present even Slight Work for
continuous 15 minutes with the risk and
tum involved leads to severe pain and
increased swelling okay please feel free
to read
thanks this is the same thing here okay
so notice the 7th of December 2016 this
information here the seventh this the
same that's it here right on that same
day after briam G sent the report to man
life insurance B from J reported she is
feeling less pain today and then
afterwards everything else was just not
correct my report was being misconstrued
again okay manual life made the the
physiotherapist change my um my medical
record to State I was doing better
okay be feel free to pause and read okay
it was being suggestive as if I'm doing
other things okay thank
you it's a there's a better um
uh a closer view of the clinical notes
okay being very suggestive he's saying
there is more swelling today more
swelling you understand it's like what
is this what are they try to do to me
okay please feel free to pause and read
thank you
okay and just oh perfect this is a 20
minute session just to show you I did I
timed it and it's all it's less than 20
minutes but here they have tens and Ice
15 minutes okay T machine and ice so
they put the ice and the T machine in my
hand and they put the ice on top of my
risk and wrap it around in an in in hand
towel e a hand towel wrap wrap on and
then I had the machine in my hand and
then he will leave the room then he will
return and for maybe 5 minutes of
massage I didn't get 5 minutes massage
so that was my 20 minutes every single
time I go to the clinic nothing changed
okay but my remember my injury was from
June so whatever he was doing was not
working okay please feel free to pause
and read thank
you I have brought um the clinical nose
forward again for a reason I've
extracted the information as you can see
okay so as soon as my life insurance got
my um Fitness abilities report right on
December 7th all of a sudden my clinical
notes were dist started as I explained
so here I've extracted the information
that's here so for a better view right
he says um December 7th 2016 he actually
said um no she has lots of swelling
present remember he had said that right
no she has lots of present swelling
present that's right here then
afterwards December
7th again the same day he recorded she
is feeling less pain okay on December
14th he made mention same above so in
other words she's feeling less pain then
on December 19th 2016 there is he
indicated there is more swelling today
as if well it's not it was not my work
something else I'm doing he giving uh
this is very he was giving um um s
suggestive uh information to make it
seem as if I was doing other things okay
however what they should have been doing
they made sure that
whatever they're doing at the clinic it
it is also consistent when I go to any
other medical you see they did not know
my movement they did not know so I
brought this forward because I saw Dr
James Chang on the 13th of of of
December and as you can see I was at
clinic on the 14th of December I saw Dr
James strong on the 13th of December and
it did say it did say on physio no
improvement he's seen my hand from
August into September into October and
he saw my hand Dr James Chang my family
doctor saw my hand on um December 13 and
said no improvement yet this
physiotherapist big ramet um um because
of Manny life wrote that I I was feeling
less
pain less pain I know my doctor canot
see my pain or whatever but he did his
test it he examined me so he knew that
there was no improvement I was still in
pain
okay um at had to wait 4 months as you
can see to see a um a specialist all
right please feel free to pause and read
thank
you okay then just just to just for to
refresh right you see as Dr James ch
indicated on physio no improvement all
right Dr James sh never offered once to
have an ultrasound x-ray or MRI
examination of my right so soul and
painful hand first seen in August I
followed up with Dr James Chang about
three times regarding the appointment of
a specialist on September 15 2016 I was
told by Dr James Chang that he would
refer me to a specialist okay I was
waiting two weeks later I followed up by
phone but was was told unsuccessful um
visited Dr James ch's office on 13 2016
I was told still unsuccessful but will
inform but will inform me as soon as
they were able to fight a specialist on
my I visited Dr James Jang in December
2013 2016 and inquired again right this
time I was folling told that an
appointment was scheduled for January 26
2017 as um with Dr Handelman okay
referred to Dr hesman I waited 3 months
before my family doctor was able to
provide a specialist for my injury I had
to wait an extra month which would have
would make 4 months without the
necessary care or treatment for my right
hand June 2016 to January 26 17 would
make 7 months with injury okay please
feel free to pause and read okay thank
you and I have
uh um part two of this as I continue to
give my representation on man life
insurance discrimination okay thank you